

ABOUT ME

A dedicated and highly skilled Java Spring Developer with an Electronic Engineering Degree and over 6 years of software development experience. Have developed cloud solutions in an agile environment for banking, insurance and educational organizations.

SKILLS

9 / 10

Java Spring Boot and RESTful Webservices.

8 / 10

AWS Cloud development

9 / 10

Jenkins, Git and GitHub, Docker, Maven

8 / 10

Enterprise Microservices Architecture

6 / 10

DevOps Continuous Integration and Jira

8 / 10

Postman, Mockito, Junit, Sonar

8/10

IntelliJ and a MacBook

7/10

Java Design patterns

EDUCATION

BEng Electronic Engineering

National University of Science and Technology 2002

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

NAB / Melbourne / May 2019 - present

Worked in an Agile squad in the Document management department in one of Australia's leading banks.

- Developing and supporting a cloud microservice based document management service application for the bank.
- Attending to Jira tasks to implement requirements from users.
- Participated in all the Agile processes and ceremonies including daily stand-ups,
 backlog grooming, code reviews, retrospectives, sprint planning meetings.
- Using the architecture and the designs provided, developed and deployed clean maintainable code into AWS.

Achievements

 Wrote the apache velocity templates for the sandbox to give metadata mapping transformation information for user requests to be understood in the content managers. The sandbox environment enables prospective tenants to evaluate the document services provided.

virtusa

EXPERIENCE

Systems Engineer

FUJITSU / Melbourne / Oct 2018 - Apr 2019

Fujitsu is a leading provider of IT products and services in a global marketplace.

 Managing laptop assets life cycle using the company's web-based application. This include direceiving, deploying, repairing, storing the laptop stock

Systems Engineer

NCR / Melbourne / Jun 2018 - Oct 2018

NCR is a global leader in developing transformational transaction technologies including online banking, POS systems and mobile payments.

Upgrading ACO bag racks and Automated Teller Machines (ATMs) at various client sites throughout Victoria

Java Developer

Yanni Technologies / Johannesburg / Sep 2015 – Dec 2017

FNB is one of South Africa's biggest banks with a market capitalization of ~\$27 billion

Development of the bank's web-based stock management and order processing system using Java Spring Boot, Spring MVC,
 JUnit, Sonar, RESTful Web Services, JMS ActiveMQ and Camel, JBoss Server, Maven, liquibase, SVN, TeamCity which was running on a SQL server database. Used Agile development methodologies on Jira in developing the system.

Achievements

• Reduced technical debt by writing unit tests for code already in production increasing the test coverage from 30% to about 85%

Java Developer

AOS / Johannesburg / Nov 2007 – Sep 2010 | Dec 2010 to Sep 2015

AOS is a investment management firm providing administration on a range of investment types such as ETFs and pension funds

• Developing and supporting an online investment product and administration platform that can administer and distribute index and securities related products. This role utilized my extensive experience in Web services, Apache Wicket framework, Apache Tomcat AS, Oracle and Oracle PL/SQL Development, Hibernate, Ant, Jenkins CI.

Java Developer

Psybergate / Johannesburg / Sep 2010 - Dec 2010

Psybergate (Pty) Ltd is a South African software development, resourcing and consulting company formed in 1999 with 70 + people.

- Developed a Short Course Intake and Management System for a local University using Scrum Agile methodology. Engaged and contributed in the sprint planning, creation of user stories, pair programming, daily standups, code reviews, sprint reviews.
- Used the Java Spring, Spring MVC and JavaScript in a Hudson CI environment for the application.

INTERESTS

I am an entry level - intermediate guitar player who enjoys playing music in a band.

REFERENCES

Available on request